[light accordion music]
[轻快的手风琴音乐]
*
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
[children laughing]
[孩子们笑]
- I cannot believe I let you
talk me into this.
- 我不敢相信我让你
说服我做这件事。
- Oh, come now, Mr. Squidward.
- 噢，来吧，章鱼哥先生。
Catering is a great way for you
餐饮是您的好方法
to make a little extra money.
赚一点额外的钱。
And me to make a lot!
而我要赚很多！
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
- Any ideas?
- 有什么想法吗？
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
How's that?
怎么样？
- Perfect, now get out there
- 完美，现在出去吧
and feed the rest of those kids.
并喂养其余的孩子。
[children screaming]
[孩子们尖叫]
- They all seem so...
- 他们看起来都很...
full of germs!
充满细菌！
- Why, of course
they're full of germs.
- 为什么，当然
它们充满了细菌。
They're kids.
他们是孩子。
Why do you think I'm wearing
this full-body latex covering?
你为什么认为我穿着
这个全身乳胶覆盖物？
[laughs]
[笑]
- Okay, I'm going in.
- 好的，我要进去了。
[inhales]
[吸气]
Krabby Patty?
克拉比·帕蒂？
[groans]
[呻吟]
- Ooh, ooh, oh,
- 哦，哦，哦，
ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh.
哦，哦，哦，哦。
- You're contaminating the food.
- 你污染了食物。
Just pick one.
就选一个吧。
- [sneezes]
- [打喷嚏]
[laughs]
[笑]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
I've been infected!
我被感染了！
[children munching]
[孩子们咀嚼]
- [vomits]
- [呕吐]
[children screaming]
[孩子们尖叫]
- Hey, kids, I'm a--
- 嘿，孩子们，我是——
[children screaming]
[孩子们尖叫]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- No, no, no!
- 不，不，不！
- Hey, I'm not paying you
- 嘿，我不会付钱给你
to play hide-and-seek.
玩捉迷藏。
These children
want to be entertained.
这些孩子
想要被娱乐。
Get down here.
下来吧。
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- I want a balloon animal.
- 我想要一只气球动物。
- Uh, um.
- 呃，嗯。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- What is it?
- A rock.
- 这是什么？
- Whoa!
[screaming]
- 哇！
[尖叫]
- Okay, birthday boy.
- 好吧，生日男孩。
Take a swing
at that piñata, son.
挥杆
儿子，在那皮纳塔上。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- Oof.
- 噢。
[laughs]
[笑]
Don't hit nice old Mr. Krabs.
别打好心的老螃蟹先生。
It's the piñata you want, son.
这就是你想要的皮纳塔，儿子。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[coins clinking]
[硬币叮当作响]
- Me money!
- 我的钱！
Do I look like
a piñata to you, boy?
我看起来像吗
给你一个皮纳塔，男孩？
- Yes, get him!
- 是的，抓住他！
- [chuckling]
- [轻笑]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
[children cheering]
[孩子们欢呼]
*
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Higher!
Go higher!
更高！
走得更高！
[heavy metal music]
[重金属音乐]
Uh, don't forget to take
your shoes off before bouncing.
嗯，别忘了带走
弹跳前脱掉鞋子。
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
[explosion]
- Ow!
[爆炸]
- 噢！
- [exclaims]
- [惊呼]
We have to
get out of here.
我们必须
离开这里。
These children are menaces.
这些孩子是威胁。
- They tore off my head.
- 他们扯下了我的头。
- [exclaims]
- [惊呼]
Maybe we should make
a break for it, Mr. Krabs.
也许我们应该做
休息一下吧，蟹老板。
- I want my birthday cake.
- 我想要我的生日蛋糕。
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- Cake, cake!
- 蛋糕，蛋糕！
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- Come on, men, let's cheese it!
- 来吧，伙计们，让我们干酪吧！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[all grunting]
[全都咕哝]
- Oh, my, are you
the high-class caterers
- 哦，天哪，你是吗？
高级餐饮服务商
I hired for an extraordinarily
large sum of money?
我受雇于一个非凡的
一大笔钱？
- Yes!
- No!
- 是的！
- 不！
- Yes.
- 是的。
- No!
- 不！
- Yes.
- 是的。
- I do not have time
for this tomfoolery.
- 我没有时间
对于这种愚蠢的行为。
I have a mansion
full of very high-class guests
我有一座豪宅
挤满了非常高级的客人
waiting for very
high-class catering.
等待非常
高档餐饮。
Are you they
or are you nay?
你是他们吗
或者你不？
- Indubitably, madam.
We are your high-class caterers.
- 毫无疑问，女士。
我们是您的高级餐饮服务商。
- But where are your tuxedos?
- 但是你的燕尾服在哪里？
- Tuxedos?
Oh, just give us a moment
- 燕尾服？
哦，请给我们一点时间
to suit up, me good lady.
穿好衣服，我好女士。
- Now, where are we going
to get tuxedos from?
- 现在，我们要去哪里
从哪里得到燕尾服？
- You.
- Hey, what are you--
- 你。
- 嘿，你是什么——
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Ew.
呃。
- Ready to serve you,
Miss Money Bags--
- 准备好为您服务，
钱袋小姐——
er, I--I mean, ma'am.
呃，我——我是说，女士。
- Very nice.
Here is your payment.
- 很不错。
这是您的付款。
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
- Mr. Krabs, you can't
take that check.
- 蟹老板，你不能
拿着那张支票。
We're not high-class caterers.
我们不是高级餐饮服务商。
- We are anything we need to be
- 我们是我们需要成为的任何人
for me to make this money.
让我赚到这些钱。
Unless you wanna go back
to the kids' party.
除非你想回去
去孩子们的聚会。
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
all: No!
全体：不！
- That's what I thought.
- 我就是这么想的。
Then start setting up inside.
然后开始在里面设置。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
- This place
is so shiny.
- 这个地方
是那么闪亮。
- Yeah, and so are the people.
- 是的，人们也是如此。
- Oh, there's no way
these people are gonna think
-哦，没办法了
这些人会想
our junk food is high class.
我们的垃圾食品是高档的。
- Hmm, you might be right.
- 嗯，你可能是对的。
SpongeBob, go find something
to fancy-up the food.
海绵宝宝，去找点东西吧
来装饰食物。
- Fancy.
Got it, Mr. Krabs.
- 想要。
明白了，蟹老板。
- Good, now I'll just get
the lay of the land around here.
- 很好，现在我就得到
这里周围的地形
- I want my birthday cake!
- 我想要我的生日蛋糕！
- Great Neptune's ghost!
- 伟大的海王星的幽灵！
- I want my cake!
I want my cake!
- 我想要我的蛋糕！
我想要我的蛋糕！
- Hey, kid, easy, easy.
Just calm down, will ya?
- 嘿，孩子，简单，简单。
冷静点，好吗？
I got your cake.
- You did?
我拿到了你的蛋糕。
- 你做到了？
- Yeah, yeah.
- 是啊是啊。
Your birthday cake
你的生日蛋糕
is right through here.
就经过这里。
- Where?
I don't see any--
- 在哪里？
我没有看到任何——
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Won't be seeing him again
any time soon.
不会再见到他了
很快。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- I. Want. My.
- 我想。我的。
Birthday. Cake!
生日。蛋糕！
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
- I want my birthday cake!
- 我想要我的生日蛋糕！
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
- What do you think
of this, Mr. Krabs?
- 你觉得怎么样
蟹老板，这个？
I call it "Krabby Pâté."
我称之为“蟹肉酱”。
Classy, huh?
优雅，是吧？
Serve it while it's hot,
Patrick.
趁热吃吧
帕特里克.
- SpongeBob, were those
jewels on the patties?
- 海绵宝宝，是那些
馅饼上的珠宝？
- Yeah. You said
"Fancy-up the food,"
- 是的。你说
“把食物打扮得漂漂亮亮的”
so I found some
shiny stuff for garnish.
所以我找到了一些
闪亮的装饰物。
Got a whole box.
- What the--
拿到了一整盒。
- 什么是--
[gasps]
SpongeBob, you can't
[喘气]
海绵宝宝，你不能
just go around taking
people's precious jewels!
只是到处走走
人民的宝贵财富！
- Well, I'm sorry, Mr. Krabs.
- 好吧，对不起，蟹老板。
I was just doing
what you told me.
我刚刚在做
你告诉我的。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Don't worry about it.
Just tell me
别担心。
告诉我吧
where you got them gems from.
您从哪里获得宝石。
- Oh, upstairs.
- 哦，楼上。
I went left, then right,
then double and triple right,
我向左走，然后向右，
然后右二右三右，
then down, up, and right
18 more times.
然后向下、向上、向右
还有18次。
Then do four somersaults,
a barrel roll,
然后翻四个筋斗
桶卷，
jump backwards twice,
spin till you get sick...
向后跳两次，
旋转直到你生病...
[gags]
And you're there.
[笑点]
你就在那里。
- Okay.
- Fancy foods!
- 好的。
- 美味的食物！
Get your fancy foods here!
在这里享用你的美味佳肴吧！
[chewing]
[咀嚼]
Delicious.
可口的。
- I love delicious stuff.
My turn!
- 我喜欢好吃的东西。
轮到我了！
[gobbling]
[狼吞虎咽]
Yummy.
好吃。
- I'll take a slice of that.
- 我要切一块。
- Mine!
- 矿！
[growls]
[咆哮]
- Ouch!
- [barking]
- 哎呀！
- [吠叫]
[gobbling]
[狼吞虎咽]
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
[plate shatters]
[盘子碎裂]
- Who wants food?
- 谁想要食物？
I'm a mindless drone
with food.
我是一架没有头脑的无人机
与食物。
Working for the man.
Huh?
为男人工作。
啊？
[light jazz music]
[轻爵士乐]
[shimmering]
[闪烁]
- Ooh.
- 哦。
- [clears throat]
- [清喉咙]
- Here you go, princess.
- 给你，公主。
[chuckling]
[轻笑]
*
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- Let's do this thing.
- 让我们做这件事吧。
[shrill squeaking]
[尖锐的吱吱声]
Hey, where you going?
嘿，你要去哪里？
[shrill squeaking]
[尖锐的吱吱声]
Oh, down here.
哦，在下面。
[shrill squeaking]
[尖锐的吱吱声]
I never heard
of a marching quintet.
我从来没有听说过
行进五重奏的一部分。
[squeak]
Uh, wait for me.
[吱吱]
呃，等我一下。
Wait, wait, wait, wait for me.
Wait, wait--
等等，等等，等等，等等我。
等等，等等——
[clarinet squeaking]
[单簧管吱吱声]
Hey, hey!
嘿嘿！
[clarinet squeaks]
[单簧管吱吱声]
- All right, what did he say?
- 好吧，他说什么？
18 rights,
then four lefts, or five?
18 项权利，
那么剩下四个，还是五个？
Ooh.
哦。
- I want my birthday cake!
- 我想要我的生日蛋糕！
- [screams]
Oh, you--get off.
- [尖叫]
哦，你——下车。
Enough of this.
[grunting]
够了。
[咕噜声]
- If you don't get me my
birthday cake, I'll set off...
- 如果你不明白我的意思
生日蛋糕，我就出发了……
- [screams]
- All these fireworks.
- [尖叫]
- 所有这些烟花。
- Give me those.
- 给我那些。
Young boy like yourself
像你一样的年轻男孩
shouldn't be playing
with fireworks.
不应该玩
与烟花。
They're too dangerous.
他们太危险了。
- Gosh, no one ever cared
enough about me to explain that.
- 天哪，从来没有人关心过
关于我的事已经足够解释这一点了。
It's like you're
my real father.
就好像你是
我真正的父亲。
May I hug you?
我可以拥抱你吗？
- Ooh.
- 哦。
- Mr. Krabs?
- 蟹老板？
- [screams]
Oh, uh, quick, in here.
- [尖叫]
哦，呃，快点，到这里。
- Why, father?
Why?
- 为什么，父亲？
为什么？
- Mr. Krabs?
- 蟹老板？
- Um, yes, ma'am?
- 嗯，是的，女士？
- Mr. Krabs, we seem
to be having some problems
- 螃蟹先生，我们似乎
遇到一些问题
with the food service.
与餐饮服务。
- Mine, mine!
- [gags]
- 我的，我的！
- [笑声]
- Mine, mine!
- 我的，我的！
- Uh, I'll be right down
to have a look.
- 呃，我马上下来
看看。
Just need to
find something here.
只需要
在这里找到一些东西。
All right, where was I?
好吧，我刚才在哪儿？
Four somersaults
and a barrel roll, I think.
四个跟头
我想还有桶卷。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- [yelling]
- [大喊]
[growls]
[咆哮]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
- Patrick, no.
- 帕特里克，不。
The food is for the guests.
食物是给客人吃的。
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
*
[clarinet honks]
[单簧管鸣响]
- What the--?
[inhales]
- 什么--？
[吸气]
[exhales]
[呼气]
- So then, I was all like--
- 所以那时，我就像--
Oof.
Well, I never.
钱币。
嗯，我从来没有。
- Food fight!
- 食物大战！
[all murmuring]
[大家窃窃私语]
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
- Oh, my.
- 哦，天哪。
- Whoa.
[belches]
- 哇哦。
[打嗝]
This must be the place.
一定是这个地方。
Hello?
Ooh.
你好？
哦。
Ooh-ee.
哦，呃。
That is one big--
water bed?
那是一件大事——
水床？
- Birthday cake!
- Dogfish.
- 生日蛋糕！
- 角鲨。
- Hi, Daddy!
- Don't call me that.
- 嗨，爸爸！
- 别这么叫我。
And stop jumping
on that water bed.
并且停止跳跃
在那水床上。
You'll pop it.
你会弹出它。
- Okay, Daddy.
- 好吧，爸爸。
- Get over here.
- 到这里来。
Why, you little--
- Hah, Daddy!
为什么，你这个小——
- 哈，爸爸！
- [growls]
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- [咆哮]
- 哇，哇，哇！
- Uh-oh.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- 呃哦。
- 哇，哇，哇！
[splash]
[溅]
[all yelling]
[大家大喊]
- Stop it, everyone!
- 停下来，大家！
You're ruining my par--
[exclaims]
你毁了我的标准——
[惊呼]
Oh, no, you did not.
哦，不，你没有。
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- Barrel roll,
four somersaults.
- 桶滚，
四个跟头。
[water splashing]
[水花四溅]
Look out, flood's a-coming!
小心，洪水来了！
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- Nice doing business with you.
- 很高兴与您开展业务。
- Come back here!
- 回到这里！
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- Huh?
- 啊？
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
[skidding]
[集材]
Whoa!
哇！
[fuse sizzling]
[保险丝滋滋作响]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[sniffs]
[嗅嗅]
Oh, no.
哦，不。
[rockets hissing]
[火箭嘶嘶声]
all: Ooh.
全体：噢。
[screaming]
[尖叫]
*
- [cheering]
- [欢呼]
My cake!
我的蛋糕！
- My check!
- 我的支票！
- My party!
- 我的派对！
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]